<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node name="Quiz" unique_id="21" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="187" is_bold="1" foreground="#c061cb" ts_creation="1702835674" ts_lastsave="1704216735">
    <rich_text>
9. What tool (command) is used to test connectivity to a computer.
Ans.) Ping


10. What protocol matches MAC addresses to IP addresses?
 Ans.) ARP
 
 
11. What tool is a GUI (graphical user interface) tool for scanning a network?
 Ans.) Zenmap
  
  
12. What tool captures network traffic and can be used to identify endpoints from that traffic?
 Ans.) Wireshark
 
 
 Updated:


13. Which type of reconnaissance involves collecting information from publicly available sources, such as websites, social media, and public records?
 Ans.) Passive Reconnaissance
 

14. What is the primary focus of footprinting in the reconnaissance phase?
 Ans.)  Collecting detailed information about the target's network and systems
 
 
15. What is the primary responsibility of the Network layer in the OSI model?
 Ans.) Logical addressing and routing


16. Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for end-to-end communication, flow control, and error correction?
 Ans.) Transport Layer
 
 
17. Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for translating data between the application and lower layers, including encryption and compression?
 Ans.) Presentation Layer
 
 
18. What is the purpose of the TTL (Time-to-Live) field in the IP header at the Network layer?
  Ans.) To limit the number of hops a packet can take through the network
  
  
19. Which protocol operates at the Network layer and is commonly used for logical addressing and routing on the Internet?
 Ans.) IP
 
 
20. What is the primary role of the UDP (User Datagram Protocol) in the Transport layer?
 Ans.) Fast and Connectionless Communication
  

21. How many packets are exchanged during the TCP three-way handshake?
 Ans.) 3
 
 
22. What is the significance of network mapping in the reconnaissance phase of penetration testing?
 Ans.) t provides a blueprint of the target network architecture
 
 
23. Which host discovery technique involves sending ICMP Echo Request packets to potential hosts and analyzing their responses?
 Ans.) Ping Sweeping
 
 
24. In ping sweeping, what is the purpose of adjusting the Time To Live (TTL) value in ICMP packets?
 Ans.) To limit the number of hops
 
 
25. What is the purpose of the "-PE" option in Nmap's host discovery scans?
 Ans.) To perform a ping sweep using ICMP Echo Request


26. Which Nmap option is commonly used for host discovery and sends ICMP Echo Request packets to determine the status of a host?
 Ans.)  -sn
 
 
27. What is the significance of using the "-p-" option in Nmap's port scanning?
 Ans.) Scans all TCP ports


28. Which Nmap option is used for performing a UDP port scan to identify open UDP ports on a target host?
 Ans.) -sU
 
 
29. In Nmap, what does the "--version-intensity" option control in service detection?
 Ans.)  The aggressiveness of service version detection
 
 
30. How can script categories be specified when using the Nmap Scripting Engine?
 Ans.) --script=category
 
 
31. Which Nmap option is specifically designed for firewall evasion by splitting large packets into smaller fragments?
 Ans.) --fragments
 
 32.) Which output format in Nmap provides a machine-readable format that can be easily parsed by scripts and tools?
 Ans.) -oG
 
 
 33.) System/Host based attacks are attacks that are targeted towards a specific system running a specific operating system?
 Ans.) True
 
 
34.) What year was Metasploit officially released to the public?
 Ans.) 2003
 
 
35.) The Metasploit Framework is open source and the codebase is publicly available on GitHub.
 Ans.) True
 
 
36.)Encoders are used to encode payloads with the aim of evading signature based AVs.
Ans.) True


37.) What directory is the Metasploit Framework installed in by default on Kali Linux?
 Ans.) usr/share/metasploit-framework
 
 
38.) What programming language is used to develop MSF modules?
 Ans.) Ruby
 
 
39.) What type of MSF modules are used to perform functionality associated with information gathering?
 Ans.) Auxiliary Modules
 
 
40.) Which one of the following commands can be used to setup and initialize the Metasploit Framework database?
 Ans.) sudo msfdb init</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
