<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node name="Quiz" unique_id="35" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="187" is_bold="1" foreground="#c061cb" ts_creation="1704025366" ts_lastsave="1707982892">
    <rich_text>
37.) An Information disclosure vulnerability is a type of vulnerability that could potentially allow an attacker to remotely execute arbitrary code on a target system.
 Ans.) False
 
 
38.) Which one of the following is not a frequently exploited Windows service?
 Ans.) SAMBA
 
 
39.) Which one of the following ports is used by RDP?
 Ans.) 3389
 
 
40.) The cadaver utility can be used to upload files on to a WebDAV server.
Ans.) True


41.) Which one of the following file extensions cannot be executed on a Microsoft IIS web server?
Ans.) .py


42.) Which one of the following commands can be used to upload malicious .asp payloads with cadaver?
Ans.) put /PATH-TO-FILE/payload.asp


43.) Which one of the following commands can be used to authenticate with a target system with PsExec?
Ans.) psexec.py Administrator@192.168.1.1


44.) PsExec authentication is performed via SMB.
 Ans.) True
 
 
45.) Which one of the following CVEs was assigned to the EternalBlue vulnerability?
 Ans.)  CVE-2017-0144


46.) The EternalBlue exploit takes advantage of a vulnerability in SMBv1.
 Ans.) True
 
 
47.) The BlueKeep exploit could potentially allow an attacker to execute arbitrary code on a Windows target.
 Ans.) True	
 
 
48.) Which one of the following commands can be used to execute a malicious executable with elevated privileges with the Akagi tool?
 Ans.) Akagi64.exe 23 C:\Temp\payload.exe


49.) In order to elevate privileges by bypassing UAC, you will need access to a user that is a member of the local administrators group.
 Ans.) True
 
 
50.) Which one of the following meterpreter commands can be used to enumerate user privileges?
 Ans.) getprivs
 
 
51.) In order to impersonate an access token, you will need to have access to an account with the "SeImpersonatePrivilege"?
 Ans.) True
 
 
52.) Bash is the default shell used by most Linux distributions.
 Ans.) True
 
 
53.) The Shellshock vulnerability affects both Windows &amp; Linux.
 Ans.) False
 
 
54.) In certain cases, FTP can be configured to allow anonymous connections.
 Ans.) True
 
 
55.) SSH only supports username/password authentication.
 Ans.) False
 
 
56.) Which one of the following commands can be used to enumerate shares with SMBMap?
 Ans.) smbmap -H 192.168.1.1 -u admin -p password123


57.) smbclient provides users with an ftp-like console interface.
 Ans.) True</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
